INTRO TO DATABASE TOOLS
数据库工具简介
IntelliJ IDEA has some handy database tools
IntelliJ IDEA有一些方便的数据库工具
for working with databases from right inside your IDE.
用于从IDE内部直接使用数据库。
We’re going to give you tips for using the database tools in IntelliJ IDEA.
我们将为您提供在IntelliJ IDEA中使用数据库工具的提示。
First you'll need to add a new data source via our Database tool window.
首先，您需要通过我们的数据库工具窗口添加一个新的数据源。
Here you can add a new data source from a number of providers.
在这里，您可以从许多提供商处添加新的数据源。
Here we’ll choose a SQLite database.
在这里，我们将选择一个SQLite数据库。
If we have a driver already installed,
如果我们已经安装了驱动程序，
we'll be able to simply add that without any further configuration.
我们将能够简单地添加它而无需任何进一步的配置。
I'll need to specify the database file, so, if I have a database dump,
我需要指定数据库文件，因此，如果我有数据库转储，
I can import that directly, test the connection to see that it works,
我可以直接导入它，测试连接以查看它是否有效，
and apply to see what the database looks like.
并申请查看数据库的外观。
IntelliJ IDEA will import the database schema.
IntelliJ IDEA将导入数据库模式。
On the right side in the database tool window...
在数据库工具窗口的右侧...
if you expand some of the nodes,
如果您扩展某些节点，
you'll see a number of columns inside these tables
您会在这些表中看到许多列
but this isn't very helpful.
但这不是很有帮助。
If you’d like to view the schema visually,
如果您想直观地查看架构，
you can press Ctrl+Shift+U to show the visualization
您可以按Ctrl + Shift + U来显示可视化
and you'll see how tables are related to each other
然后您将看到表之间如何关联
by the foreign key here.
通过这里的外键。
You can also navigate any of the tables by using your navigation keys.
您也可以使用导航键浏览任何表。
You can jump to its source and then press it again
您可以跳至其来源，然后再次按
to open up a table.
打开桌子。
If you want to reform a query against some tables in this database,
如果您要针对该数据库中的某些表重新创建查询，
you can open up the console window and write some SQL.
您可以打开控制台窗口并编写一些SQL。
From the console window, you'll get code completion and static analysis
在控制台窗口中，您将获得代码完成和静态分析
for whichever dialect of SQL you're using.
无论您使用哪种SQL方言。
In the join condition, it'll offer to autocomplete the foreign key for me.
在加入条件下，它将为我自动完成外键。
I can just select that and it'll automatically complete it.
我可以选择它，它会自动完成。
I can execute this query by pressing Ctrl+Enter.
我可以通过按Ctrl + Enter来执行此查询。
Inside the result window, you'll see all the results for the query we just ran.
在结果窗口内，您将看到我们刚运行的查询的所有结果。
THANKS FOR WATCHING!
感谢收看！